The question was asked, how to create a bat speed in hitting. Well one of the things we need to do then to make sure that we have the strongest body possible, so we need to get in the workout room and work on our body to make sure that we have all the strength that we can muster with the body that the good Lords given us.
The other thing that we need to do is be able to use our entire body during the swing.
That creates more velocity in the bat, and also creates more force.
The force and the velocity combined makes the ball go further.
There's several things to note when we consider batting speed, and that's the use of our core section and the lower part of our body.
One of the things we're going to need through the swing, is balance.
To create that balance we need the nice triangle that keeps the knees inside our feet throughout the swing.
The knees need to stay in this position inside our feet.
The other thing that we need to do is to make sure that we use our hips and our legs to get through the swing before the bat gets there, because that helps with bat velocity.
To do that we're going to take a toe touch, and once the heel is planted, this back knee is going to start to turn.
As the bat knee turns it's still ahead of the bat, and as we start the bat to the ball it's going to be we're going to be completely rotated by the time we get the knob to the ball in a position of bat lag.
We need to have this back foot perpendicular with the ground on our toe, this front side firm and straight with our front knee, and this back knee bent in the knee behind knee position.
This extra use of our lower body and core section will help us with our bat velocity, our bat speed.
So make sure that you use your lower half and your core section throughout your swing, and you get in the appropriate sequence.
But we're basically going to go, we're going to take a negative move to gain some momentum, we're going to make a toe touch, heel plant, bat lag, contact, palm up palm down, with our arms still slightly flexed, throw the bat to position of extension, about chest high, and finish above our shoulder.
The lower the pitch, the higher we're going to finish, the higher the pitch, the lower we're going to finish.
But make sure that when you're trying to create bat speed, that you make sure that you use your lower section of your body to create extra force and extra bat speed.
The combined use of your entire body, especially getting this back knee turned and your back hip through, will create more bat velocity.
And that's how you create more bat speed in hitting.